人们渴望大冰封之前的生活
People long for life before the Freeze.
但不好说
But I dunno.
我或许更喜欢这样的生活
I might like this life better.
威尔福德工业
我想到妈妈
I think of me mum.
在餐桌前一根接一根地抽烟
Chain-smoking at the kitchen table,
昨晚的妆容下是新的瘀伤
fresh bruises under last night's makeup.
"脑袋要转得勤" 她会说
"Keep your head on a swivel," she'd say,
"麻烦会不期而至"
"'cause trouble comes sideways."
现在是个零和世界
It's a zero-sum world now.
你开始一件事
You set a thing in motion
看着它一点点推进
and watch it tumble down the line.
要发生的一切 都迎头而来
All that's comin' is comin' head-on...
6点罢工 为妮基伸张正义 为三等厢伸张正义
这一场大闹剧
...the whole great shitshow
压扁成了一条直线
flattened down into a single line.
为了攀爬 要有别人摔下去
To climb, someone else falls.
为了获得 要有别人失去
To gain, someone else loses.
我们一圈圈地转
And roundy-round we go.
1001节车厢
1,001 cars long.
雪国列车
第一季 第六集
电力
附属列车 312平台 电力短路
Subtrain, platform 312. Electrical short.
我去
I'll go.
电力
好 有趣的工作都归你了
Sure, have all the fun jobs, man.
你甚至不需要遵守规章
And you don't even have to follow protocol.
多棒啊
Isn't that nice?
你想要什么 哈维
What do you want, Javi?
你想要援引威尔福德的
You wanna invoke Wilford's
"不得在永动机厢亲近"规则吗 是吗
"no fraternizing in the Engine" rule, is that it?
她刚上车时 说我们要遵守他的命令
When she first took this train, she said we'll follow His order.
但我猜 她可以把审判变成一场骗局
But I guess she can turn a trial into a total sham.
你也可以上女佣 是吧
You can shag the help, too, right?
哈维
You know, Javi,
都快七年了
it's almost been seven years.
或许你该找个女友
Maybe you should find a girlfriend.
但我还得对她撒谎
Only I'd have to lie to her, too.
注意呼吸
Focus on your breath.
你在动
You're squirming.
沉浸于当下
Be in the moment.
嗯 我沉浸了
Yep, I'm in the moment.
就是...
Just...
我需要进入别的时刻
some other moments I kinda need to be in.
梅
Mel!
你睁眼睛了吗
Are your eyes open?
没有
Nope.
你真没用
You're useless!
你都不能试试吗
You can't even try?
对不起 珍珠
I'm sorry, Jinju.
今天没心情
Just not feeling it today.
听说罢工的事了吗
Heard about the strike?
罢工
Strike?
嗯 可以给我拉拉链吗
Yeah. Can you zip me?
看
Look.
三等厢在传
They're circulating all through Third.
这是审判的后果
It's blowback from the trial.
该死
Shit!
他们能让列车的系统停摆
They can cripple every system on the train.
是的
Yes, they could.
他们会跟我们一样受罪
They'd suffer along with the rest of us.
他们在拿枪指着自己的脑袋
They're putting the gun to their own head.
看来 为了让权力天平向己方倾斜
Well, it seems like, to pull the balance of power their way,
他们不惜冒险
they're willing to risk it.
你打算怎么办
What are you gonna do?
我要
I'm going
镇压反叛
to crush it.
我忘记问你了
I forgot to ask you.
昨晚怎么样 跟提尔
How was last night, with Till?
昨晚没发生什么
There was no last night.
她没来
She never showed up.
奇怪啊
That's weird.
-司闸员提尔 -你去哪了
- Brakeman Till. - Where have you been?
我找了你一整晚
I looked for you all night.
为什么呢
And why is that, then?
听着 奥斯维勒 我很抱歉发生了那事
Listen, Osweiller, I'm sorry about what happened.
我做了一个两难的决定 一个坏决...
I made a split decision, a bad dec--
不 我们晚点再谈这事
No, we've got time for that later.
我们还要去执法呢
We have law enforcement work to be doing.
跟我来
Follow me.
整理下仪容
Fix yourself up, yeah?
没事的
It's okay.
你没事 没事了
You're okay. It's okay.
你醒了 你只是在做梦 你之前在做梦
You're awake. You're just dreaming. You were dreaming.
我怎么到这来的
How'd I get here?
乔茜带你来的
Josie brought you.
她说你被放进抽屉了
She said they put you in a drawer.
安德烈 发生了什么
Andre, what happened.
你干了什么
What did you do?
我干了什么
What did I do?
我干了他们要求的事 我破了他们的案子
I did what they asked me. I solved their crime.
那他们为什么惩罚你
Then why would they punish you?
要小心自己许的愿 不是吗
Careful what you wish for, huh?
你把我带出了车尾
You drag me out of the Tail, hm?
你说你爱我
You tell me that you love me?
-我差点就信了 -我也是
- I almost believed it! - So did I!
那晚我们结束了
We ended that night!
我不想谈论那晚
I don't wanna talk about that night!
你就应该别脏了自己的手
You should've kept your hands clean!
你就不该把我牵扯进去
You should've left me out of it!
那你的这些愤怒
Then, all of this rage that you feel,
-责怪 都可以变得纯粹 -安德烈
- all of the blame, then it would've been pure! - Andre!
你要告发我吗
Are you gonna turn me in?
不
No.
腐败的威尔福德婊子
Corrupt Wilford whore!
法西斯 垃圾
Fascist! Scum!
安静
Silence!
威尔福德先生注意到
It has come to Mr. Wilford's attention
有人策划在今天搞罢工活动
that a work stoppage is planned for today.
威尔福德先生想提醒大家
Mr. Wilford would like to remind you
你们的劳动是神圣的
that your labor is sacred!
作为不付钱的乘客
As non-paying passengers,
这还是你们的车票
it is also your ticket aboard.
这就是条件
These are the terms.
我们都有自己的地位和工作
We all have our places and our jobs
-威尔福德先生期望... -我们让列车运行
- and Mr. Wilford expects -- - We keep this train running!
我们人数众多
We have the numbers!
我们的声音要被听见
We will be heard!
够了
Enough!
你最好赶紧说完 免得房盖被掀开
You better finish up before the top pops off of this place.
如果这场罢工如期进行
If this work stoppage goes ahead,
威尔福德先生会随机选十个罢工工人
Mr. Wilford will seize 10 striking workers at random
送去车尾
and send them to the Tail.
并找十个车尾人替补他们的位置
He will bring 10 Tailies forward to fill their posts.
你们以为三等厢的生活艰苦吗
You think life in Third is bad?
后车厢还有四百人
There are 400 souls downtrain
愿意付出一切换你们的生活
who would kill for what you have!
保护好它
Protect it!
取消罢工
Call off the strike.
谢谢
Thank you.
乔茜
Josie?
你感觉如何
How are you feeling?
像起死回生
Back from the dead.
我们得带你离开这里
We've gotta get you out of here.
去哪 他都站不起来
To where? He can barely stand up.
当他们发现他失踪后
When they discover he's missing,
第一时间就会来这里找
this'll be the first place they look.
我做了安排 有人愿意帮忙
I've made arrangements. Somebody who's willing to help.
我能再见你吗
Will I see you again?
我们不能联系
There can be no more contact.
这是为了你好
It's for your own good.
我不是你们的敌人
I'm not the enemy.
安德烈
Andre.
好了 好了
Okay. Okay.
你怎么离开车尾的
How are you getting out of the Tail?
清洁小队
Sanitation.
阿斯特丽德和我对调
Astrid swaps in with me,
让我能在前车待四小时
gives me four hours uptrain.
这都是通过蟑螂能量棒来交流安排的
We arrange it all through the bug bars.
你这段时间没闲着
You've been busy.
是的
Yeah.
多亏了你的芯片
Well, thanks to your chip.
我们得走了 得赶紧走
We've gotta go. We've gotta go.
我需要告诉你一件事
I need to tell you something.
以防我遭遇什么不测
In case anything happens to me.
莱顿 你不会有事的
Layton, you're gonna be fine.
我们会找人帮你
We're gonna get you help.
威尔福德不在列车上
Wilford's not on the train.
我识破了她 所以才被关进抽屉
That's why I was drawered, because I figured her out.
-莱顿 莱顿 -专心听我说
- Layton, Layton -- - Listen to me!
威尔福德只是为了让我们听话而塑造出的假象
Wilford is an illusion to keep the rest of us in line.
梅兰妮·卡维尔才是幕后主使
Melanie Cavill is the one behind the curtain.
不能告诉任何人 包括车尾人
No one can know, not even the Tail,
我们必须先想出如何利用这点
not till we figure out how we can use this.
好的
Yes. Alright.
我们得走了 得走了
We've gotta go. We've gotta go.
谢了
Thanks.
该死
Shit!
我来过这儿
I've been here.
老天 好一幅景象
Christ, what a picture.
-是你 -来
- You! - Come.
进来 快点
Come on. Quickly.
隔离中 不得入内
躺到板子上 警探 我给你检查一下
On the slab, Detective. Let's take a look.
我...我没事
I'm -- I'm fine!
把手给我
Give me your hand.
吐了一晚上吗
Puking all night?
咳出黑色液体吗
Coughing up black fluid?
进抽屉的后遗症很大
That drawer hangover's a whopper.
让她检查你 让她检查你
Let her check you! Let her check you.
他神志清醒吗 有理智吗
How's his mind? He seem rational?
有些人出来后像植物一样没反应
Some people come out like vegetables.
还有一些则焦虑冲动
Others are agitated, impulsive.
你为什么对抽屉如此了解
Why do you know so much about The Drawers?
姑且把你归类为焦虑好了
I'll put you down as agitated.
我联系了我们的同盟
I reached out to our allies, okay?
告诉他们你病了
I told them you were sick.
他们替我找到了佩尔顿医生
They made contact with Dr. Pelton for me.
组织损伤有限
Tissue damage is limited.
至于你的大脑 可能要几天后才恢复清明
As for your melon, could be days before the fog clears.
你需要休息
You need rest.
你和他们合作
You work with them?
是这样吗
That it?
克利姆特
Klimpt.
梅兰妮·卡维尔
Melanie Cavill.
帮他们做科研
Help them with their science.
我给获释的囚犯做检查 仅此而已
I do medicals on the prisoners who are released, nothing more.
他们不是囚犯 而是试验品
They're not prisoners. They're lab rats.
那里到底是怎么回事
What the hell is going on down there?
我没权限知道
I'm not cleared to know.
那你猜一下
So guess!
不只那一节车厢
It's not just the one car.
还有11节这样的车厢
There's 11 more like it.
全是抽屉
Full of drawers.
数百个
Hundreds of 'em.
用来干什么
What for?
集体监禁 人体实验
Mass incarceration, human experiments,
法庭职权以外的关押
extrajudicial imprisonment.
是我们自己的朝鲜 藏在二等厢
It's our own little North Korea, tucked away in Second Class.
你还要这个样子多久
How long you gonna keep this up?
奥斯维勒
Osweiller!
你想从我这儿得到什么
What do you want from me?
你知道什么东西比较好吗
You know what would be nice?
一些大海里的新鲜扇贝
Some fresh scallops from the ocean.
别让珍珠也卷进来
You leave Jinju out of this.
你这样想吗
Oh, you think?
你知道吗 如果你做的事暴露出来
Do you know, if what you did comes out,
你会丢掉工作
you'll lose your job,
可能还得丢掉一只胳膊
probably an arm, too,
而珍珠呢
and Jinju, well,
她会像扔垃圾一样把你抛掉
she'll just drop you like the piece of rough that you are.
我想要的就是这个 提尔
So, here's what I want, Till --
我能得到的所有东西
every last thing I can get.
是的
Yeah,
你说得很清楚了
you've made that clear.
这列车上是有一些乐子的
There's fun to be had on this train.
我准备找点乐子
And I plan to have some.
既然我们知道你如此肮脏了
And now that we all know you're as dirty as they come,
你就得跟着一起玩 是不是
you're gonna have to play along, aren't ya? Hm?
造纸工人沃特
Walter the Papermaker.
有一些问题要问你
Got some questions for ya.
-这是从哪儿来的 -这...
- Where'd this come from? - It's --
这跟我没关系
It's got nothing to do with me.
这是自制的纸
It's, uh, homemade stock.
我能看出来
No, I can see that.
可以吗
May I?
不管是谁造的纸 他都需要原料供应
Whoever made this needed supplies.
有谁来找过你 寻求供应吗
Anyone come to you, asking?
没有 就像我说的
Uh, no, it's, uh, like I said, uh,
我对此一无所知 而且
I don't know anything about it, and --
天啊 请帮帮我
Aah! Oh! Jeez! Ah! Ah! Please help.
你怎么想 提尔
What do you reckon, Till?
这位良民有点痛苦了
This fine citizen's in some distress.
你是要帮他呢 还是...
You gonna help him, or...?
回答问题
Answer the question.
好的 好的
Okay. Okay.
是克雷
It was Clay!
夜车的那个
In -- In -- In the Nightcar!
走吧 搭档
Let's go, partner.
真有意思
This is fun!
她是一位勇士
She was a warrior.
她勇敢拼搏
She fought like hell.
而且她爱你们胜过一切
And she loved you kids more than anything.
温妮
Winnie.
温妮 走吧
Winnie, come on.
直系亲属决定如何办葬礼
Next of kin decides on burial rites.
你想要唱首歌吗
You want a song?
要做祈祷吗
Want a prayer?
振作 哥们
Hey, come on, lad.
你现在是一家之主了
You're the head of the family now.
你要为你妹妹变得坚强
You need to be strong for your sister.
不要葬礼 请人来清理吧
No ceremony. Call for disposal.
好的
Okay.
温妮
Winnie.
过来 温妮
Come on, Winnie.
我们得走了
We gotta go.
-我想要妈妈 -走吧
- I want Mama. - Come on.
-我知道 我知道 -我妈妈
- I know! I know. - My mama!
-我恨这种事 -是的
- I hate this shit! - Yeah.
我想为他们做点什么
I wanna do something for them,
为大家 振奋情绪
for everybody, lift spirits.
好
Yeah.
我需要你的帮助 奥斯
I need your help, Aus.
他们需要看到车尾外面的景象
They need to see beyond the Tail.
想不到在这里见到你
Fancy meeting you here.
想不到在哪都能见到你
Fancy meeting you anywhere.
我们应该一起逃到塔希提岛上去
We should run away to Tahiti together, you know?
抛下这一切吗
Leave all this?
这里什么情况
What do we got here?
电力短路让刹车都卡住了
Electrical short caused the brakes to seize.
我们最好让维修队严阵以待
Oh, we'd better get a Breach team on standby.
不用 我们能修好刹车的
Nah, we can free that brake.
转向架引擎承受不了这种高温
Bogie motor can't take that heat.
听到了吗
Hear that?
我去找维修队
Yeah. I'll get the Breach team.
我们得把马达换掉
We'll have to swap that motor out.
收留我们的风险可不小
You're riskin' an awful lot, takin' us in.
到了一定时候就不能再袖手旁观了
Comes a point when you can't stay on the sidelines any longer.
七年的时间可不短
Seven years is a long time.
-是什么改变了 -别这么激动 莱顿
- What changed? - Hey, ease up, Layton!
她和我们是同一阵营的
She's on our side!
不不 他说得对
No, no, he's -- he's right.
乘客文件
Passenger files.
车上每个人都有
Everyone onboard has one.
医疗记录 应享权利 住房供给
Medical history, entitlements, housing.
然后还有这个
And then there's this.
大约有十分之一的乘客有这些称号
Roughly 1 in 10 passengers has that designation.
什么意思
What does it mean?
据说有一张名单
There's rumors of a list.
一张黑名单
A blacklist.
国家公敌
Enemies of the state.
我想就是这个
I think... this is it.
为什么
Why?
因为上面有你的名字
Because you're on it.
你们俩都在上面
Both of ya.
从两周前开始
And, as of two weeks ago,
我也在上面
so am I.
变得非常简单 不是吗
Gets real simple, doesn't it?
在你变成他们目标的时候
When you the one they're coming for.
哐啷 哐啷 哐啷 呜呜
Chugga, chugga, chugga, choo-choo!
哐啷 哐啷 哐啷 哐啷 哐啷
Chugga, chugga, chugga, chugga, chugga, chugga, chugga, chugga.
大冰封前 很多人知道何为寒冷
Before Freeze, many people know cold.
在雪国列车上
On Snowpiercer,
只有维修工才知道何为刺骨寒冷
only breach worker know real cold.
新的寒冷
The new cold.
严酷
She is harsh!
还会咬人
And she bite.
只有维修工能与寒共舞
Breach worker are only one who can dance with cold.
如果你仔细听...
And if you listen...
来 大家都趴下
Come, everybody down!
-怎么了 -趴下
- What's going on? - Down.
你们可以听到
You can hear the music
寒冷放给我们听的音乐
she play just for us.
抱歉打断你们
Sorry to interrupt.
没事
No.
威尔福德先生需要你去后车厢
Mr. Wilford needs you downtrain.
好的
Okey-dokey.
记住 孩子们 当冰封降临时
Now, remember, children, when Freeze come,
世界应该感谢谁
the world, she owe everything to who?
威尔福德
To Wilford!
感谢谁
To who?!
威尔福德
To Wilford!
To Wilford.
利亚姆 迈尔斯
谢谢你来
Thank you for coming.
大家都继续学习吧
Alright, back to work, everybody.
我们的小定心丸怎么样了
How's young Miles and Miles?
我完成了你交给我的练习 卡维尔小姐
I finished that exercise you gave me, Ms. Cavill.
这是你一个人做的吗
You did this all by yourself?
自己做更简单
It's easier by myself.
我看它就像看图片一样
I see it like pictures.
我想也许你应该教教我
I think maybe you should be teaching me.
做得好 迈尔斯
Great work, Miles.
利亚姆 迈尔斯
跟我谈谈
Talk to me.
我觉得自己活了无数次
I feel like I've lived so many lives,
也死过无数次
died so many times.
大冰封
The Freeze,
车尾 链条
the Tail, the Chain.
永远都不会结束
It never ends.
我没有你这种勇气
I don't have your courage.
我看到的不是这样
That's not what I see.
如果你坚持罢工
If you go through with this strike,
最后你可能会沦落到车尾的
you could end up in the Tail.
你觉得那里很糟糕
Bad as you think it is back there,
相信我 比你想象中更糟糕
trust me, it's worse.
而你从那里出来了
And you got out.
那也需要很大的勇气 扎拉
And that did take courage, Zarah.
我们是斗士
We're fighters.
我们要保护我们爱的东西
We protect the things we love.
恭喜
Congratulations.
Congratulations!
谢谢
Thank you.
所有乘客请注意
Attention all passengers.
780号车厢出现机械故障
There's been a mechanical disruption in Car 780.
以防万一 该区乘客会被暂时疏散
The section will be temporarily cleared as a precaution
三等厢附属列车将被封锁 等候另行通知
and Third Class subtrain is restricted until further notice.
如造成不便 我们深表歉意
We apologize for the inconvenience
多谢乘客们的配合
and we thank you for your cooperation.
我得回清洁小队那边去
I've got to get back to Sanitation.
佩尔顿医生会留在这里陪你
Dr. Pelton's gonna stay with you.
那就是她
That's her.
她居然还是列车之声
She's even the goddamn voice of the train.
一次只做一件事 好吗
One thing at a time, okay?
休息一下吧
Get some rest.
他会好的
He's gonna be fine.
只是需要时间
It's just gonna take time.
感激不尽
I can't thank you enough.
他偷了我的芯片
He stole my chip.
莱顿 莱顿
Layton! Layton!
莱顿
Layton!
糟了
Shit!
莱顿 莱顿
Layton! Layton!
莱顿
Layton!
停下 别去
Stop, stop, stop!
她说了她在哪 我能找到她
She told me where she is. I can get to her.
不行 你脑子不清楚
No, no! You're not thinking straight!
她不知道我出来了
She doesn't know I'm out.
我可能再也找不到这么好的机会了
I might never get another chance like this.
回到里面来 你需要休息
Come back inside! You need to rest.
我们明天再讨论这个 做个计划 好吗
We can talk about this tomorrow, make a plan, okay?
该死 莱顿
Goddamn it, Layton!
莱顿
Layton!
该死
Shit!
首先 我要知道
First, I'd like specifics
机械故障的具体细节
about the mechanical issue.
有个转向架马达需要更换
It's a bogie motor swap-out.
-日常事务 -你运气真好
- It's routine. - Lucky you.
你可以穿上破衣服
You get to put on some grubbies.
威尔福德让我看着
Wilford wants my eyes on it.
你知道他的
You know how he is.
我以为我知道
I thought I did.
我能问你一件事吗
Can I ask you something?
你觉得他最近怎么样
How does He seem to you, these days?
为什么这么说
Why do you ask?
我是说
Well, I mean,
他今天似乎恢复了往常的状态
He seems to be back on form today,
谢天谢地 但三等厢的事情
thank God, but this business in Third,
老实说
I mean, to be honest,
我觉得是他自找的
I think He asked for it.
在审判时那样纵容他们
Indulgin' them at the trial like that?!
你不能对这些人置若罔闻
You cannot spare the rod with these people, you know.
你得采取雷霆手段予以压制
You've got to hammer down!
露丝 记住
Ruth, remember.
平静的服务
Calm Hospitality...
-才有平静的列车 -才有平静的列车
- ...Calm Train. - ...Calm Train.
好了 波吉 它出去了
Alright, Boki, she's out!
把它拉上来
Let's lift her up!
动起来 动起来 快
Move, move, move! Let's go! Let's go!
吊起发动机 把它拿出来
Hook up the motor. Let's get her out!
莱顿
Layton!
你好 威尔福德先生
Hello, Mr. Wilford.
跟上 迪马科 快跟上
Catch up, DiMarco, catch up.
我知道你在做什么
I know what you're doing.
数以百计的名字 你的那些名单
The hundreds of names, your lists!
任何人只要出言不逊 或有非分之想
Anyone has a bad word, has an unsanctioned thought,
就会被扔进抽屉 是吗
they get thrown in a drawer, yeah?
-继续吗 -再来 再来
- More? - Yes, yes, yes!
把它弄上来
I need her up here!
-上来 继续 -好的 上去了
- Up here. Keep going. - Okay. Up we go.
不 你不明白
No, you don't understand.
看着我的脸
Look at my face.
最后抓到你的是车尾人
It was a Tailie that got you, in the end.
该死 该死
Shit! Shit!
-别动它 -迪马科 不
- Leave her alone! - DiMarco! No!
系统警告
警告 请坐稳扶好
Warning. Please brace.
实行紧急封锁
Emergency lockdown in effect.
-怎么回事 -警告 请坐稳扶好
- What was that? - Warning. Please brace.
-我抓住你了 我没事 -实行紧急封锁
- I got you. I'm okay. - Emergency lockdown in effect.
后退 你还好吗
Stay back. You good?
-继续 -好 走 走
- Keep going. - Okay. Go. Go.
好的 好的
Okay, okay.
莱顿 放开我
Layton, let me go.
列车需要我
The train needs me.
好
Okay.
抽屉车不是你想的那样
The drawers aren't what you think.
抽屉车就是地狱 我的人还在里面
The drawers are hell and my people are still in there!
那不是监狱
They're not a prison!
那是救生船
They're a lifeboat.
我们命悬一线了
We're hanging by our nails.
莱顿
Layton,
我们命悬一线了
we're hanging by our nails.
整个人体实验
The whole goddamn human experiment,
一块霉菌就能毁掉
it can be undone by a bloom of mold.
如果社会秩序崩塌了
If the social order collapses,
如果资源耗尽了
if resources fail,
如果机械故障了
if mechanics fail,
我们最大的希望就是进入假死
our best hope is to keep life in suspension,
让人们保持冬眠状态度过大冰封
to keep people in stasis while we ride out this Freeze.
400个人
400 people.
他们因为多样性 健康和能力而被选中
They were selected for diversity, for health, for skills,
让我们有机会在另一边战斗
to give us a fighting chance on the other side!
你决定谁生谁死
You decide who lives and who dies.
不 我们一起做的决定
No. We all made that choice,
登上列车的那一刻
when we boarded this train
我们把别人丢在后面
and we left people behind.
列车快不行了 莱顿
This train's dying, Layton.
拜托 让我修好她
Please, let me fix her.
主液压出故障了
We have a master hydraulics failure.
我需要一个控制器
I need a controller.
我过去
I'll go.
-好了 -你能行吗
- Okay. - You got it?
可以
Yeah.
快点 快点
Come on, come on.
怎么样
Yeah!
遥测失败
Telemetry failure.
那边的活塞没有传回任何数据 什么都没有
I'm not getting any readings from the pistons on that side, nothing!
一定是连接器 物理故障
Must be the connector, something physical.
我要穿上防护服
I'm gonna suit up.
我要去下面
I gotta go under.
让我去吧 梅
Let me go, Mel.
-让我去 -会很冷的
- Let me go. - This is cold work.
波吉才能下去
Only Boki should be going.
液压系统故障 波吉
Busted hydraulics, Boki.
你不知道规格
You don't know the specs.
我需要你做诊断
And I need you on diagnostics.
哈维 能听得到吗
Javi, can you hear me?
到底发生什么了
What the hell is going on, guys?
-和我说说 -好 把速度降到最低
- Talk to me. - Okay, take it down to dead minimum speed.
我们在哪
And where are we?
还有多久到托雷塔峡谷
How long till Torreta Canyon?
正在减速
I'm taking her down.
在最低速度下 永动机到峡谷
But at minimum speed, the canyon's gonna be
还有大约八分钟
about eight minutes to the Engine.
离我们还有多久
How long till us?
14分钟 怎么了
14 minutes to you. Why?
因为 以这个角度
Because, at this angle,
这节车厢撞到托雷塔峡谷的时候
when this car hits Torreta Canyon,
整列火车都会脱轨
the whole train's gonna derail.
完蛋了
Holy shit.
是啊
Yeah.
确实是"完蛋了"
"Holy shit's" Right.
我设计了她
I designed her.
我会修好她
I'll fix her.
把我封起来
Seal me in.
你真是个混蛋
You're a dick!
你知道吗
You know that?
我不能看着你虐待他人还坐视不管
I'm not gonna stand by while you abuse people.
我们快死了 提尔
We're about to die, Till.
好吧 那这就是我临终前最后的话
Fine. Then these are my last words.
我不会让你敲诈我的
I won't let you extort me
你就是个混蛋
and you're a dick.
我搞不懂你
I don't get you.
对很多小事非常正直
So righteous on the small stuff,
但面对重罪的时候 你却又格外变通
but pretty darn flexible, when it comes to high crimes.
莱顿本不该进抽屉的
Layton shouldn't have been in the drawers!
那你还不该把我锁在外面呢
Yeah, and you shouldn't have locked me out!
感觉不对劲
Something's going on!
你有过自己被蒙在鼓里的感觉吗
Don't you ever feel like you're being kept in the dark?
奥斯维勒
Osweiller.
你正在想谁呢
Who are you thinking about right now?
谁都没想 我满脑子都是我自己 滚开
No one. Just me. Bugger off.
关掉手电 关掉灯
Torches out! Lights off!
-把灯关掉 -把灯关掉
- Lights out! - Lights out!
我想给你们看一件你很久很久都未见过的东西
I wanna show you something you haven't seen in a long, long time.
天呐
Holy.
看
Look.
外面看起来就是这样的吗
Is that what the outside looks like?
真棒
Nice.
摄像头上线
Camera feed online.
我的天哪
Oh, God.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我们代表威尔福德先生和威尔福德工业
on behalf of Mr. Wilford and Wilford Industries,
向您在这段难挨的时光表现的沉着与合作
we'd like to thank you for your composure
表示由衷的感谢
and cooperation during this trying time.
在我们应对可能的脱轨过程中
As we prepare for possible derailment,
请时刻铭记
we ask that you please remember
您的转移安全指令
your in-transit safety directive --
在原地做好准备
Brace in place.
我再次重申 在原地做好准备
I repeat, brace in place.
请所有乘客 在此次
We beg that all passengers remain calm
前所未有的紧急状况中保持冷静
in the face of this unprecedented emergency.
伙计们 我到桥边了
Guys, I'm at the bridge.
我重复 永动机到桥边了
I repeat, the Engine's at the bridge.
六分钟 梅
Six minutes, Mel!
我们还有六分钟
We've got six minutes!
正在开启
Opening now.
上帝啊 这太疯狂了
Jesus Christ. This is crazy.
太疯狂了
This is crazy.
应该在你正前面 梅
Should be directly in front of you, Mel.
不要够得太远了
Don't reach out too far for that thing.
抓住它 抓住它 梅 快点
Grab it. Grab it, Mel. Go, go, go, go!
见鬼了
Shit!
五分钟 五分钟
Cinco minutos. Cinco minutos.
我知道这感觉
I know it seems like
我们快完了
this might be the end,
但并不是的
but it's not.
也不可能是
It can't be.
看在上帝的份上 这可是雪国列车
This is Snowpiercer, for God's sake!
我们是地球上仅剩的生存者
We are the last of Earth's survivors
我只是
and I just...
我们会活下来的
We are going to make it.
我就是知道
I just know it.
我们会挺过去的
We just will.
威尔福德先生曾带领我们摆脱过更糟的困境
Mr. Wilford has gotten us out of worse scrapes before.
保持信念
So keep the faith.
只要记住
And you just remember
他的永动机永不停息
that His Engine always provides.
找到一个人
So find someone
抱紧他们
and hold them close.
还有拜托
And, please,
尽量保暖
try to stay warm.
人渣
You shit!
你个人渣 人渣
You shit! You shit! You shit!
是你做的吗
Did you do it?
-是你做的吗 -不是
- Did you do it?! - No!
列车遭受的损伤很严重 乔茜
The damage to the train is bad, Josie.
我脑子里唯一的念头就是想要见你
All I could think was I wanted to see you.
80秒 梅
80 seconds, Mel.
80秒
80 seconds.
梅 你可以的
Right, Mel. You got it.
你可以的 梅
You got it, Mel.
你可以的 你可以的
You got this. You got this.
加油
Come on!
加油 梅
Come on, Mel!
60秒
60 seconds!
加油 加油 加油啊
Come on. Come on. Come on. Come on. Come on. Come on.
-你还好吗 梅 你没事吧 -我们得回去找她
- You okay, Mel? You alright? - We need to go back for her!
等一下 波吉
Hold on a second, Boki.
你还好吗 梅
You alright, Mel?
我没事
I'm okay!
太好了
Ye-e-e-s!
怎么样
How about that?
液压系统恢复了 太好了
Hydraulics are online! Yes!
太好了 冲啊
Si, si, vamos!
冲啊 我操
iVamos, carajo!
提升到运行速度 哈维
Increase to running velocity, Javi.
好了各位 我要提速了
Alright, guys. I'm bringing her up to speed.
安全
All clear.
回到岗位
Return to stations.
安全
All clear.
你还好吗 克雷
You okay, Clay?
你硬要知道的话
I was thinkin' about my mum
我在最后想的是我妈妈
at the end, if you must know.
你想她吗
You miss her?
当然不 她就是垃圾
Oh, God, no. She was trash.
她醉酒后很恶劣 清醒的时候更糟 不过是的
She was a mean drunk, even worse sober, but, yeah,
我想的就是她
that's who I was thinkin' about.
他们最终会抓到莱顿的
They're gonna catch Layton eventually.
你的所作所为迟早会曝光
It's gonna come out, what you did,
无论我说不说出去
whether I spill it or not.
好了 搭档  你该
Alright, partner. You should,
去找你的妻子了
go find your girl.
她在那
There she is.
好了
Okay.
十根手指 一个鼻子
Ten fingers! One nose!
很好 我们做到了
Okay, okay! We did!
你太棒了
You are kind of amazing.
小菜一碟
Piece of cake.
你还好吗
You okay?
没事
It's okay.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我应该在的
I should've been there.
我昨晚应该去找你的
I should've shown up for you last night.
不重要了 你现在来了
It doesn't matter. You're here now.
你还有别的事吗
Is there something else?
如果
What --
如果我不是你以为的那个人怎么办
What if I'm not the person you think I am?
怎么了
What's going on?
你可以跟我说
You can talk to me.
没什么
Nothing.
我只是很开心来这儿
I'm just happy to be here.
我需要喝一杯
I need a drink.
我们没事
We're okay.
我爱啤酒 我爱啤酒
I love beer! I love beer!
全天候给我供应啤酒
You give me your beer all day!
大家喝起来
Everybody drink now!
这太美了
This is beautiful!
你
Hey, you!
谢谢
Thank you!
安静
Quiet down.
Quiet down!
谢谢
Thank you!
雪国列车的人们
People of Snowpiercer,
触摸一个表面
touch a surface.
快啊 把手放在任何东西上
Go on. Put your hand to something, anything.
快啊
Go on.
感受下
Feel it.
慢慢感受
Take it in.
那是我们神圣的嗡嗡声
That is our sacred hum.
那是我们的心跳
That's our heartbeat.
它在咆哮
And she's roaring!
轨道动荡可阻止不了我们
It's gonna take more than a bit of track turbulence to stop us!
说得好
Okay!
敬
A toast
永动机
to the Engine Eternal!
敬伟大的威尔福德先生
To the great Mr. Wilford!
威尔福德 威尔福德
Wilford! Wilford!
-威尔福德 威尔福德 -喊起来
- Wilford! Wilford! - Come on!
威尔福德 威尔福德
Wilford! Wilford!
看样子三等厢的人回心转意了
Looks like the people of Third have had a change of heart.
庆祝会结束 但他们的委屈不会
The celebration will end, but their grievances won't.
下次 可不会有灾难来拯救他了
Next time, He won't have a disaster to save Him.
奥德丽
Hey, Audrey.
看看气氛
Read the room.
-我们还活着 -威尔福德 威尔福德
- We're alive. - Wilford! Wilford!
-威尔福德 -威尔福德 波吉
- Wilford! - Wilford! Boki!
波吉 波吉
Boki! Boki!
这不是车尾 不过
Well, it's not the Tail, but,
我希望能凑合
I hope it'll do.
你确定吗
Are you sure about this?
我偶尔和一个档案室的人共住一个房间
I bunk with a guy from Archives from time to time.
鼾声超大
Snores like a leaf blower, but,
-但我能忍 -谢谢你
- I'll suffer through. - Thank you.
很高兴看到你复活
Well, it's nice to see you back among the living.
锁上门 有人敲门的话
Keep the door locked and, if anyone knocks,
假装你不在
pretend you're not here.
因为你阿斯特丽德被困在了车尾
You know, Astrid's stuck in the Tail because of you.
他们会照顾好她的
They'll take good care of her.
我们要怎么应付梅兰妮
What are we gonna do about Melanie?
我不想谈论梅兰妮
I don't wanna talk about Melanie.
好
Okay.
那你挑个话题
You pick a topic, then.
带他过来
Bring him in.
你知道这是什么吗
Do you know what this is?
卡尺
A caliper.
每个工程师都需要一把
Every Engineer needs one.
威尔福德先生给我的
Mr. Wilford gave me this.
我想送给你
I want you to have it.
威尔福德先生有求于你 迈尔斯
There's something Mr. Wilford needs from you, Miles.